<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Arnav Patil</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Arnav Patil</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>CHANGE ME</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 19:29:10 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>First-Year Engineering Calendar (Arnav&#39;s Version)</title>
			<link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-year/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 19:29:10 -0600</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-year/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[%!s(<nil>)]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I&rsquo;ve received a lot of DMs from incoming Frosh on Discord and LinkedIn asking me to give feedback on first-year courses, I&rsquo;ve decided to provide my advice for each course.</p>
<h1 id="fall-semester">Fall Semester</h1>
<h2 id="aps100-orientation-to-engineering">APS100: Orientation to Engineering</h2>
<ul>
<li>Grading for assignments is abritrary and harsh &ndash; so don&rsquo;t skip tutorials (you might need the tutorial grades).</li>
<li>Get to know your TA and listen when they talk about their experiences.</li>
<li>Make note of the resources they provide &ndash; even though the lecture delivery is questionable, you might find yourself needing the resources.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="aps110-engineering-chemistry-and-materials-science">APS110: Engineering Chemistry and Materials Science</h2>
<ul>
<li>Take good textbook notes, then add extra content covered in lectures.</li>
<li>Highly recommend attending Prof. Ramsay&rsquo;s 9:00 AM lectures.</li>
<li>Use Prof. Ramsay&rsquo;s videos to revisit any content you didn&rsquo;t understand the first time.</li>
<li>Tutorials are generally good, and they&rsquo;re helpful to attend around quiz/midterm time.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="aps111-engineering-strategies-and-practice-i">APS111: Engineering Strategies and Practice I</h2>
<ul>
<li>Pay attention to the readings, they&rsquo;re more helpful than you might first think.</li>
<li>Buy full-year access to the Perusall textbook, there&rsquo;s more material to cover in APS112.</li>
<li>This semester will either genuinely make you wonder how some of your classmates were accepted into UofT Engineering or leave you with your new best friends.</li>
<li>Make sure you use every opportunity to earn the extra PD points though, as only 10 PD points will add a whole percentage to your final grade!</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="civ100-mechanics">CIV100: Mechanics</h2>
<ul>
<li>Aaaah yes, the course with the highest first-year kill count.</li>
<li>I wish I had put more effort into this course, especially by doing more practice problems, and asking my questions earlier.</li>
<li>If you like it, good for you, but if you&rsquo;re indifferent to this course, just do your best to pass and move on.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mat186-calculus-i">MAT186: Calculus I</h2>
<ul>
<li>Essentially everything you&rsquo;ve covered in calculus till date (with the addition of some topics in ODEs, I really hope they keep that this year).</li>
<li>Midterms and assignments were a bit funky, and as class rep I always had people complaining that they got zeroes on the assignments because they forgot to sign the academic integrity statement (so don&rsquo;t forget to do that).</li>
<li>While I did poorly in this course, there are other reasons I wasn&rsquo;t a big fan of it: I had a few run-ins with a TA and a professor that really jaded my view, and I made sure to let them know during course evals.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mat188-linear-algebra">MAT188: Linear Algebra</h2>
<ul>
<li>Pay attention to the course readings, and make good use of the textbook if you don&rsquo;t understand any of the content discussed in class.</li>
<li>This was also a course where I regretted not spending more effort to do more practice problems and past midterms.</li>
<li>Learn MATLAB, you&rsquo;ll very likely be using it in your upper-year courses.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="winter-semester">Winter Semester</h1>
<h2 id="aps105-computer-fundamentals-taken-summer-2024">APS105: Computer Fundamentals (taken Summer 2024)</h2>
<ul>
<li>A much better programming course compared to its counterpart (APS106).</li>
<li>One thing that did strike me, however, is that the pace of the content was easily manageable in the summer despite being accelerated (fall-winter courses are four months, summer is less than 2); this made me wonder about the pace of the course during the winter semester.</li>
<li>Overall, a good course, and it&rsquo;s the only course that is mandatory for transfers into ECE.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="aps106-fundamentals-of-computer-programming">APS106: Fundamentals of Computer Programming</h2>
<ul>
<li>A generic first course in computer programming using Python.</li>
<li>I went into this course with no prior coding experience, and found it extremely straightforward with consistent practice.</li>
<li>Make sure you understand what&rsquo;s going on in the labs, and <strong>use the lower averages to ride the curve to the top LOL.</strong></li>
<li>I will also say that as an Indy (industrial engineering student) at the time of taking this course, I found that APS105 (C) would have been much better preparation for second-year programming courses.</li>
</ul>
<p>This course will at some point become EXT&rsquo;d for me because I don&rsquo;t need it as an ECE student. But until then, I&rsquo;ll take the extra boost on my GPA!</p>
<h2 id="aps112-engineering-strategies-and-practice-ii">APS112: Engineering Strategies and Practice II</h2>
<ul>
<li>No comments. Like ESP I but worse in most ways.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="ece110-electrical-fundamentals">ECE110: Electrical Fundamentals</h2>
<ul>
<li>W course, W content, W professors (especially Xilin Liu). By far my favourite and one of the easiest courses of winter semester.</li>
<li>Some of you may have an advantage in that you&rsquo;ve covered part of the content. Use the textbook if you don&rsquo;t understand the E&amp;M concepts, and attend tutorials for the circuits part because it&rsquo;s free practice for solving circuits (trust me you&rsquo;ll be needing it).</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t bother putting down past questions and exams on your cheatsheet, it&rsquo;s not worth it &ndash; instead, focus on including important concepts and proceudres, see <a href="/files/firstyear/ece110formulae.pdf">the one I used in my final exam</a>, for example.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mat187-calculus-ii">MAT187: Calculus II</h2>
<ul>
<li>Well-taught course for the most part (I only really took issue with the methods used to teach the sequences and series unit).</li>
<li>As an ECE/MIE/T1 student, you&rsquo;ll learn all of the last unit (vector-valued calculus) in MIE100, and I have heard rumblings of that being taken out of the curriculum.</li>
<li>Practice practice practice!!!!!! Learn your lessons from Calc I and Linear Algebra.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mie100-dynamics">MIE100: Dynamics</h2>
<ul>
<li>There&rsquo;s generally a lot of controversy over which course is harder between CIV100 and MIE100. I think that it comes down to what you learned in high school physics; the Alberta high school physics curriculum puts more emphasis on dynamics over statics, which is why I found this course significantly easier.</li>
<li>The teaching team is great, and the support they provide makes MIE100 a better course than CIV100 any day.</li>
<li>Make sure you understand the assignment questions and the examples covered in class, everything on the midterm and exam will be a combination of something you&rsquo;ve seen before.</li>
<li>Oh, and don&rsquo;t forget to draw reaction forces for simple harmonic motion diagrams! (see that happened to my buddy once)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mie191-intro-to-mechanical-and-industrial-engineering">MIE191: Intro to Mechanical and Industrial Engineering</h2>
<ul>
<li>Great seminar course, highly recommend attending.</li>
<li>You get to learn a lot of cool things about your discipline such as what industry and research opportunities are available.</li>
<li>Keep in mind not all 191 courses are structured the same, for example, to earn a CR in ECE191, you have to attend 9/12 lectures, whereas in MIE191 you need to finish a short assignment at the start and end of the semester.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
