<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arnav Patil</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arnav Patil</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CHANGE ME</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:24:23 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ECE241</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/secondyear/ece241/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:24:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/secondyear/ece241/</guid>
      <description>Digital Systems (with Verilog) Notes Textbook Notes&#xA;Course Description Copying from the Academic Calendar until I can write my own description of the course:&#xA;Digital logic circuit design with substantial hands-on laboratory work. Algebraic and truth table representation of logic functions and variables. Optimizations of combinational logic, using &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t cares.&amp;rdquo; Multi-level logic optimization. Transistor-level design of logic gates; propagation delay and timing of gates and circuits. The Verilog hardware description language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAT290</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/secondyear/mat290/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:24:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/secondyear/mat290/</guid>
      <description>Advanced Engineering Mathematics Notes Textbook + Readings Notes Repo&#xA;Course Description Copying from the Academic Calendar until I can write my own description of the course:&#xA;An introduction to complex variables and ordinary differential equations. Topics include: Laplace transforms, ordinary higher-order linear differential equations with constant coefficients; transform methods; complex numbers and the complex plane; complex functions; limits and continuity; derivatives and integrals; analytic functions and the Cauchy-Riemann equations; power series as analytic functions; the logarithmic and exponential functions; Cauchy&amp;rsquo;s integral theorem, Laurent series, residues, Cauchy&amp;rsquo;s integral formula, the Laplace transform as an analytic function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAT291</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/secondyear/mat291/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:24:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/secondyear/mat291/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Mathematical Physics (Calculus III) Notes Textbook + Readings Notes Repo&#xA;Course Description Copying from the Academic Calendar until I can write my own description of the course:&#xA;The chain rule for functions of several variables; the gradient, directional derivative, tangent plane and small signal modeling and Jacobians. Multiple integrals; change of variables and Jacobians, line integrals: parametric and explicit representations, the divergence and curl of a vector field, surface integrals; parametric and explicit representations, multi-variable Dirac Delta distribution, superposition of vector fields, Helmholtz decomposition theorem, Divergence theorem and Stokes&amp;rsquo; theorem and application from electromagnetic fields.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Year Engineering Calendar (Arnav&#39;s Version)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 19:29:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-year/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve received a lot of DMs from incoming Frosh on Discord and LinkedIn asking me to give feedback on first-year courses, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to provide my advice for each course.&#xA;Fall Semester APS100: Orientation to Engineering Grading for assignments is abritrary and harsh &amp;ndash; so don&amp;rsquo;t skip tutorials (you might need the tutorial grades). Get to know your TA and listen when they talk about their experiences. Make note of the resources they provide &amp;ndash; even though the lecture delivery is questionable, you might find yourself needing the resources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:39:57 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Arnav, and I&amp;rsquo;m a second-year student studying Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE) at the University of Toronto, with a double Minor in Artificial Intelligence and Engineering Business. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in exploring computer hardware and machine intelligence.&#xA;Outside of classes, I&amp;rsquo;m involved with the University of Toronto Engineering Society as a Project Director and the IEEE University of Toronto Student Branch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APS105</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps105/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps105/</guid>
      <description>Computer Fundamentals Notes Textbook Notes + Lecture Excerpts&#xA;Course Description APS105: Computer Fundamentals is a first-year programming course taken by undergraduate students at the University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science and Engineering. Though any first-year may opt to take this course, it is a prerequisite for second-year studies in Electrical and Computer Engineering. It is also taken by most TrackOne (general engineering) students. This course teaches students to code in the C programming language; the other disciplines, and those who opt not to learn C, take APS106: Fundamentals of Computer Programming (which teaches Python).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APS106</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps106/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps106/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentals of Computer Programming Notes Textbook Notes&#xA;Course Description APS106: Fundamentals of Computer Programming is a course taken by most first-year undergraduates at the University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science and Engineering. The disciplines that take this course are: Mech, Indy, Chem, Civ, Min, and MSE. According to the Academic Calendar, this course teaches basic concepts in software systems and algorithms, and utilizes the Python language.&#xA;I took this course in Winter 2024, and ended the course with an A+.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APS110</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps110/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps110/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Chemistry and Materials Science Notes Textbook Notes + Lecture Excerpts&#xA;Course Description APS110: Engineering Chemistry and Materials Science is a course at the University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science and Engineering. According to the Academic Calendar, the course is built on the principle of the structure-property relationship. This is one of the five courses taken by ALL undergraduates in the Fall semester of their first year.&#xA;I took this course in Fall 2023 under Professor Scott Ramsay.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APS111</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps111/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps111/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice I Notes Lecture Notes + Textbook Excerpts&#xA;Course Description Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice (ESP) is a two-course program within the first-year curriculum at University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science &amp;amp; Engineering. These are introductory design courses, meaning that students work in teams on projects brought forward by real-life clients. In the fall semester, all groups work on one of a few projects brought forward by the same client (Hart House in my year, and Sidney Smith Commons the year prior).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APS112</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps112/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/aps112/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice II Notes Lecture Notes + Textbook Excerpts&#xA;Course Description Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice (ESP) is a two-course program within the first-year curriculum at University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science &amp;amp; Engineering. These are introductory design courses, meaning that students work in teams on projects brought forward by real-life clients. In the fall semester, all groups work on one of a few projects brought forward by the same client (Hart House in my year, and Sidney Smith Commons the year prior).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
