<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arnav Patil</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arnav Patil</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CHANGE ME</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 16:48:10 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 16:48:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Test post. Just making sure my blog actually works!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:39:57 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Arnav, and I&amp;rsquo;m a second-year student studying Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE) at the University of Toronto, with a double Minor in Artificial Intelligence and Engineering Business. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in exploring topics in computer hardware and machine intelligence. Outside of classes, I&amp;rsquo;m involved with the University of Toronto Engineering Society and the IEEE University of Toronto Student Branch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Course Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/</guid>
      <description>On this page, I&amp;rsquo;ve curated a collection of course notes. These notes are mainly final exam review or transcribed textbook/lecture notes. I hope you find them as helpful or insightful as I did!&#xA;Last Update: MAT188 &amp;ndash; all 12 sections finished.&#xA;First Year Fall APS110: Engineering Chemistry and Materials Science&#xA;APS111: Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice I&#xA;MAT188: Linear Algebra&#xA;Winter APS105: Computer Fundamentals (taken in Summer 2024)&#xA;APS106: Fundamentals of Computer Programming</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAT187</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat187/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat187/</guid>
      <description>Calculus II Notes Readings Notes&#xA;Course Description MAT187: Calculus II is a course taken by all first-year undergraduates at the University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science and Engineering. This course is a standard second course in calculus, with a focus on engineering contexts.&#xA;I took this course in Winter 2024 under Professors Shai Cohen and Camelia Karimianpour. This was, in my opinion, the hardest course I took all semester, and I often found myself struggling and feeling left behind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAT188</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat188/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat188/</guid>
      <description>Linear Algebra (Engineering) Notes Readings Notes&#xA;Course Description MAT188: Linear Algebra is a course at the University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science &amp;amp; Engineering. This is a standard first course in linear algebra, and is one of the five courses taken by ALL undergraduates in the Fall semester of their first year.&#xA;This notes package is in no way a complete representation of the course. That being said, these notes cover all the content in the course readings, which are the Pre-Class Essentials (to be read before the lecture) and the Post-Class Readings (to be read after).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
