<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arnav Patil</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arnav Patil</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CHANGE ME</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 19:29:10 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arnav&#39;s Review of First Year Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-year-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 19:29:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-year-classes/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve received a lot of DMs from incoming Frosh on Discord and LinkedIn asking me to give feedback on first-year courses, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to provide my comments on each course, as well as its course average.&#xA;Fall Semester APS100: Orientation to Engineering Great course in theory but not so much in practice. APS100 is meant to introduce a lot of the Faculty&amp;rsquo;s and University&amp;rsquo;s resources to students, and also help us get on our feet through assignments such as creating a task list and weekly schedule.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:39:57 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Arnav, and I&amp;rsquo;m a second-year student studying Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE) at the University of Toronto, with a double Minor in Artificial Intelligence and Engineering Business. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in exploring topics in computer hardware and machine intelligence. Outside of classes, I&amp;rsquo;m involved with the University of Toronto Engineering Society and the IEEE University of Toronto Student Branch.&#xA;Feel free to reach out!&#xA;LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/arnavpatil/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Course Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/</guid>
      <description>On this page, I&amp;rsquo;ve curated a collection of course notes. I hope you find them as helpful as I did! If you have any questions or feedback, feel free to reach out to me at arnav.patil@mail.utoronto.ca&#xA;Last Update: MAT291 &amp;mdash; chapter 13.5 added.&#xA;First Year Fall APS110: Engineering Chemistry and Materials Science&#xA;APS111: Engineering Strategies &amp;amp; Practice I&#xA;MAT188: Linear Algebra (Engineering)&#xA;MAT224: Linear Algebra II (Arts &amp;amp; Science) &amp;mdash; left incomplete :(</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAT187</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat187/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat187/</guid>
      <description>Calculus II Notes Readings Notes&#xA;Course Description MAT187: Calculus II is a course taken by all first-year undergraduates at the University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science and Engineering. This course is a standard second course in calculus, with a focus on engineering contexts.&#xA;I took this course in Winter 2024 under Professors Shai Cohen and Camelia Karimianpour. This was, in my opinion, the hardest course I took all semester, and I often found myself struggling and feeling left behind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAT188</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat188/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat188/</guid>
      <description>Linear Algebra Notes Readings Notes&#xA;Course Description MAT188: Linear Algebra is a course at the University of Toronto&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Applied Science &amp;amp; Engineering. This is a standard first course in linear algebra, and is one of the five courses taken by ALL engineering undergraduates in the Fall semester of their first year.&#xA;I took this course in Fall 2023 under Professor Camelia Karimianpour. This course is, on paper, not terribly challenging, and definitely not the hardest of the courses taken by first-year undergraduates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAT224</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat224/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:36:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/firstyear/mat224/</guid>
      <description>Linear Algebra II Notes Textbook Notes&#xA;Course Description I didn&amp;rsquo;t take MAT224: Linear Algebra II myself, but after MAT188 was done kicking my ass, I knew I wanted to take some time in the summer to review linear algebra. So, when I noticed this course covers mostly the same content as MAT188 with a little extra, I ordered the course textbook, A Course in Linear Algebra by Damiano and Little.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
